Guide to the Lynne Sagalyn Research Files for "Power at Ground Zero" 1972-2016 MS 3128
New-York Historical Society
* "World Trade Center Memorial and Redevelopment Plan Programmatic Agreement," April 22, 2004. Related document: Draft version, March 25, 2004.
* PANYNJ, "Transcript of WTC Transportation Hub Permanent WTC PATH Terminal Section 106 Consulting Parties Meeting—November 4, 2004."
* FTA, NYSHPO, ACHP, and PANYNJ, "Memorandum of Agreement Regarding the WTC Transportation Hub," April 19, 2005.
* "World Trade Center Site Resource Protection Plan for Construction of the WTC Transportation Hub Project," September 2005.
* Letter to the Margareta Morera [PANYNJ] from Elizabeth S. Merritt and Roberta Lane [National Trust for Historic Preservation], "Re: Comments on Preliminary Cumulative Effects Analysis (Feb. 3, 2006 Posting) Tower Perimeter Column Remnants and Tower Footprint Areas," February 24, 2006.
* LMDC, "Presentation to Section 106 Consulting Parties," July 12, 2006; September 29, 2006.
* LMDC and PANYNJ, "Vesey Street Stair Remnant, LMDC Section 106 Meeting," July 12, 2006.
* FTA, "Approach to Cumulative Effects Analysis for the Lower Manhattan Recovery Effort," July 14, 2003.
* LMDC and PANYNJ, "World Trade Center Memorial and Redevelopment Plan—Historic Resources Report," January 2005; Related documents: July 2005, January 2006, July 2006, January 2007, July 2007, January 2008, July 2008, January 2009, July 2009, January 2010, July 2010, January 2011, July 2011, January 2012.
* PANYNJ, "The Port Authority of New York and New Jersey Analysis of Potential Cumulative Effects on the WTC Site Historic Resource, Tower Footprint Areas (Restatement), Preliminary Draft for Discussion Only, June 29, 2006 Posting." Related documents: "Preliminary Analysis of Potential Cumulative Effects on the WTC Site Historic Resource, Tower Perimeter Column Remnants and Tower Footprint Areas, February 3, 2006 Posting;" "Continued WTC Site Preparation Work for the WTC Transportation Hub, January 16, 2008 Posting."
* PANYNJ, "World Trade Center (WTC) PATH Terminal New York, New York, Construction Protection Plan for Historic Properties Adjacent to the Project," February 2006, Revised 2/24/06.
* PANYNJ, "World Trade Center (WTC) Vehicular Security Center and Tour Bus Parking Facility, New York, New York, World Trade Center Site Resource Protection Plan," June 2007.
Planning for a Cultural Program at the WTC Site
* LMDC, "Invitation to Cultural Institutions for the World Trade Center Site," June 30, 2003. Related document: Addendum Number 1, July 15, 2003; Addendum Number 2, August 18, 2003.
* LMDC, NYS Council on the Arts, and NYC Department of Cultural Affairs, "Transcript of Hearings on the Cultural Forum WTC Site," July 28, 2003.
* LMDC, "Report on the Memorial Center and Cultural Complex at the World Trade Center Site," February 10, 2004.
* International Freedom Center, "Statement by Tom A. Bernstein: Freedom Center Speech," June 10, 2004.
* LMDC, Request for Proposals, Architectural Services for World Trade Center Cultural Program: Performing Arts Complex - North Building and Museum Complex - South Building, August 2, 2004.
* International Freedom Center, "International Freedom Center: Content and Governance Report," September 23, 2005.
* International Freedom Center, "Statement [on withdrawing from the WTC site]," September 29, 2005.
* Snohetta, "The Cultural Center at the World Trade Center Site, 'Rising Above" n.d.
* "Performing Arts Center at the World Trade Center, Confidential Analysis, Draft," from the Office of the NYC Deputy Mayor for Rebuilding and Economic Development, n.d. [November 21, 2006]
Economics of Rebuilding / Liberty Bonds
* Appleseed, "Economic Impact of Redeveloping the World Trade Center Site: New York City, New York State, and the New York-New Jersey Area," October 30, 2003, commissioned by LMDC and released by Governor George E. Pataki.
* City Council City of New York, "Transcript of the minutes of the Committee on Lower Manhattan Redevelopment March 9, 2006 [Alan Gerson, chairperson].
* U.S. General Accounting Office, "Tax Administration: Information is Not Available to Determine Whether $5 Billion in Liberty Zone Tax Benefits Will Be Realized," Report to Congressional Requesters (GAO-03-1102), September 2003.
* NYC Industrial Development Agency, "Public Testimony Presented Critical of the Project and Agency Responses for World Trade Center Liberty Bonds," from public hearing of December 8, 2005.
* Project Applications New York Liberty Bond Program Commercial Facilities for Tower 1 and Retail filed by PANYNJ, June 30, 2006, Supplement July 10, 2006; for Towers 4, 3, and 2 filed by Silverstein Properties, November 24, 2009.
* New York Liberty Development Corporation, "Public Hearing Re: Proposed issuance of Qualified New York Liberty Bonds for the benefit of 2 World Trade Center, LLC, 3 World Trade Center, LLC & 4 World Trade Center LLC, and/or one or more affiliated special purpose entities," transcript, December 3, 2009.
Building a Permanent PATH Transportation Hub
* FEMA, FTA, FHWA, U.S. HUD, ESDC, LMDC, U.S. Coast Guard, U.S. EPA, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, and the National Marine Fisheries Service, "Memorandum of Understanding, Environmental Coordination and Review among the Federal Partners of the Federal Task Force to Rebuild New York City Environmental Planning and Review Committee," July 2002.
* PANYNJ, "Request for Qualifications/Request for Proposals—Performance of expert Professional Architectural and Engineering Service for the Permanent World Trade Center Path Terminal on a Task Order Basis," July 1, 2003.
* Letter to Joseph M. Allbaugh [FEMA] and Jennifer Dorn [FTA] from Governor George E. Pataki, [regarding resources for recovery from terrorist attacks of 9/11], February 6, 2003.
* PANYNJ, "World Trade Center Transportation Hub, Permanent World Trade Center PATH Terminal and Pedestrian Connections, Environmental Review Processes, Scoping Meeting, October 8, 2003, October 9, 2003.
* The City of NY, "New PATH Terminal Design: Key Urban Design Issues," n.d.
* FTA and PANYNJ, Permanent WTC PATH Terminal Project Development Agreement, February 14, 2004.
* FTA, PANYNJ, and PATH, Permanent WTC PATH Terminal Final Environmental Statement, May 2005.
* Letter to Jennifer Dorn from Governor George E. Pataki, re: resources to rebuild the transportation infrastructure of Lower Manhattan, June 3, 2005.
* PANYNJ, "Record of Decision, Permanent World Trade Center (WTC) PATH Terminal, New York, New York," June 29, 2005.
* PANYNJ and FTA, "Permanent WTC PATH Terminal Construction Agreement," May 25, 2006; Revised and Restated Construction Agreement, September 2012.
* PANYNJ and MTA Capital Construction, "Memorandum of Understanding regarding the Underpinning of the 1 Line Cortlandt Street Station and Subway," June 1, 2006.
* Letter to Governor George E. Pataki from James S. Simpson [FTA] [regarding determining eligibility for Lower Manhattan transportation recovery funds for two additional WTC projects], October 6, 2006.
* Memorandum to Governor Eliot Spitzer, Paul Francis, Tim Gilchrist, Avi Schick from Tony Shorris RE: WTC Hub Cost Reduction Options," March 7, 2008.
* U.S. Department of Transportation, Office of the Secretary of Transportation, Office of Inspector General, Baseline Report on the Lower Manhattan Recovery Projects, FTA Report Number: MH-2008-086, September 26, 2008.
* Letter to Matt Welbes [FTA] from Governor David A. Paterson, [requesting additional financing for the Transportation Hub], June 30, 2009.
* Letter from Linda Keinbaum [MTA] to Christopher O. Ward, "Re: #1 Line Cortlandt Street Station Funding Agreement," August 4, 2009.
* U.S. Department of Transportation/FTA, Project Management Oversight Program, Lower Manhattan Recovery Office, "Permanent World Trade Center Port Authority Trans-Hudson Terminal Project," Monthly Monitoring Reports, June 2006 through December 2014.
Managing the Delivery of Infrastructure and Construction
* LMCCC, "Presentation to Lower Manhattan Development Corporation Board of Directors Audit and Finance Committee Report, Wednesday, November 29, 2006.
* U.S. DOT, FTA, and LMRO, "Finding of No Significant Impact (FONSI) Documentation, World Trade Center Vehicular Security Center and Tour Bus Parking Facility," January 26, 2007. Related documents: PANYNJ, Section 106 Consulting Parties Meeting, November 29, 2005; "Public Hearing" slide deck, November 28, 2006; "WTC Site Resource Protection Plan," June 2007.
* LMCCC, "Draft Summary of WTC Site Construction Coordination," n.d. [2007].
* LMCCC, "Value Planning Risk-based Analysis Study to Validate Results of the Construction Coordination Room Process (CCR), February 20, 2007 through March 2, 2007, New York City, New York," Executive Summary, April 30, 2007.
* LMCCC, LMCCC Assessment – 2/13/08, Lastest [sic] Schedule 37 (12/31/07), Draft," February 13, 2008.
* PANYNJ, WTC Report Assessment ["Ward Report No. 1"], June 30, 2008.
* PANYNJ, WTC Design and Construction Analysis, HUB Working Group, Steering Committee Report, September 25, 2008.
* PANYNJ, WTC Report: A Roadmap Forward ["Ward Report No. 2"], October 2, 2008.
* PANYNJ, World Trade Center Quarterly Report, from 4Q2008-2Q2011.
* PANYNJ, Letter to Darrell Walters [Phoenix Constructors, JV] from Steven Plate, "WTC Transportation Hub Contract WTC-284.458GC-General Contracting Services-Work Package 4C – Demolition of Temporary Stations and H&M Structure, Work Package 4B East Side Basement, Basement Walls and Excavation Installation of Tiebacks in H&M Area," notification that vendor's contract will end September 23, 2009, n.d [2009].
Developing the Commercial Program for the WTC Site
* PANYNJ and the five lessees, World Trade Center Properties LLC collectively, "Interim Access Agreement," July 18, 2002.
* PANYNJ, Letter agreement between PANYNJ and GMAC/Silverstein WTC investors, regarding the use of insurance payments and advances ["swap agreement"] with WTC leaseholders c/o Silverstein Properties, December 1, 2003.
* PANYNJ and the five lessees, World Trade Center Properties LLC collectively, "Amendment to Leases and Reciprocal Easement and Operating Agreement," December 15, 2003.
* PANYNJ and the individual lessees, World Trade Center Properties LLC collectively, "Pre-Negotiation Agreement," December 8, 2005.
* WTC Arbitration No. 1, "Decision," December 11, 2008.
* WTC Arbitration No. 2, "Decision, Interim Award, and Supplemental Order," January 22, 2010.
1WTC
* PANYNJ, "Freedom Tower Project Authorization," staff presentation and minutes of the board meeting, February 22, 2007.
* PANYNJ, Minutes of the board meeting authorizing joint venture with the Durst Organization, August 5, 2010; update, MAY 25, 2011.
* WTC Tower 1 LLC, "Request for Proposal: Observation Deck Development and Management, One World Trade Center, New York, New York," January 27, 2012.
* Legends Hospitality LLC, "Observation Deck Development and Management Proposal," May 3, 2012.
* PANYNJ, Minutes of the board meeting authorizing lease agreement with Legends for Observation Deck Space, March 20, 2013, and slide deck presentation.
Silverstein Towers (T4, T3, T2)
* "Silverstein Properties Responds to the City's Flawed Analysis of World Trade Center Plan," SPI press release, February 9, 2006.
* NYC EDC, "World Trade Center Site Summary of Financial Analysis," presented to the New York City Council, March 2006.
* John N. "Janno" Lieber, Testimony [before City Council of New York City], March 9, 2006. Related document: "World Trade Center: The Future of Downtown," slide deck, March 9, 2006.
* SPI, Letter to Anthony R. Coscia and Kenneth J. Ringler [PANYNJ], re WTC revised "Conceptual Framework" ["2006 deal"] for the redevelopment of the WTC site, April 26, 2006.
* PANYNJ, Minutes of the Board of Commissioners meeting authorizing the "Conceptual Framework" agreement ["2006 deal"], September 21, 2006. Related document: Authorization and Execution of Agreements and Related Documents," PANYNJ Board meeting minutes, September 21, 2006.
* PANYNJ and SPI, "Master Development Agreement for Towers 2/3/4 of the World Trade Center," November 16, 2006. Amended and Restated, December 16, 2010.
* Silverstein Properties, Letter to [redacted, but likely Mayor Michael Bloomberg] from Larry Silverstein [regarding dispute over financing of the private office towers and intent to evoke arbitration mechanism under the 2006 Master Development Agreement between Silverstein Properties and the PANYNJ [, July 6, 2009.
* PANYNJ, Letter to Larry Silverstein from Anthony Coscia and Chris Ward, [regarding new proposal for financing private office space at the WTC site, July 9, 2009.
* Silverstein Properties, Letter to Anthony R. Coscia and Christopher O. Ward from Larry Silverstein, "Re: World Trade Center [response to PANYNJ July 9, 2009 letter proposal], July 16, 2009.
* John N. "Janno" Lieber, Testimony [before City Council of New York City], Testimony, August 19, 2009.
* PANYNJ, Minutes of the Board of Commissioners special meeting authorizing the WTC East Side Development Plan ["2010 deal"], August 26, 2010; update, November 18, 2010; Tower 4 Liberty Bonds Update, October 20, 2011; Tower 3 update, June 25, 2014; December 10, 2015.
Retail
* PANYNJ, Minutes of the board meeting authorizing joint venture with Westfield, January 4, 2008; February 9, 2012; December 4, 2013.
Audits and Performance Reports
* Appleseed in association with The Louis Berger Group, Inc., The Lower Manhattan Development Corporation HUD-Funded Projects & Programs: Leading Economic Revitalization in Lower Manhattan, November 2004. A second report issued August 2006.
* Good Jobs New York [joint project of the Fiscal Policy Institute and Good Jobs First], The LMDC: They're in the Money; We're in the Dark: A Review of the Lower Manhattan Development Corporation's Use of 9/11 Funds, August 2004.
* Independent Budget Office, "Three Years After: Where Is the $20 Billion in Federal WTC Aid? Number 132, August 11, 2004.
* U.S. Department of Transportation, FTA, Lower Manhattan Recovery Office [Bernard Cohen] "Report on Program Innovations," August 2004.
* Todd J. Zinser [Acting Inspector General, U.S. Department of Transportation], "Lower Manhattan Reconstruction: Lessons Learned from Large Transportation Projects," statement before the Committee on Homeland Security, Subcommittee on Management, Integration, and Oversight, U.S. House of Representatives, July 13, 2006.
* U.S. Department of Transportation, Office of the Secretary of Transportation, Office of Inspector General, "Memorandum to Deputy Federal Transit Administrator from Deputy Assistant Inspector General for Surface and Maine Programs, Subject: Notification of Major Project Monitoring for Lower Manhattan Recovery Projects Project Number: 06M9018M000," August 28, 2006.
* U.S. Department of Transportation, Office of the Secretary of Transportation, Office of Inspector General, Baseline Report on the Lower Manhattan Recovery Projects: Federal Transit Administration, Report Number: MH-2008-086, Date Issued: September 26, 2008.
* Independent Budget Office, "The Aftermath: Federal Aid 10 Years After the World Trade Center Attack," August 2011, with tables in web supplement.
* Navigant, Phase I Interim Report, presented to The Special Committee of the Board of Commissioners of the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, January 31, 2012; Phase II Report, September 2012.
Event Transcripts
Charlie Rose Show, transcripts of the following shows:
* "A Discussion with Roland Betts," September 15, 2004.
* "Interviews with Roland Betts, Paul Goldberger, Gordon Ramsay," May 27, 2005.
* "New York City's Deputy Mayor Discusses New Design for Freedom Tower," June 29, 2005.
* "A Conversation with Architects Renzo Piano and Frank Gehry; Discussion with Architectural Critic Ada Louise Huxtable," August 5, 2005.
* "Revisiting 9/11: A Talk with Architect Who Designed Freedom Tower [David Childs]" August 16, 2005.
* "A Look at World of Art and Architecture," with guests Jed Perl, Nicolai Ouroussoff, December 28, 2005.
* "Critic's New Book Explores 20th-Century Architecture [Ada Louise Huxtable]," April 2, 2009.
* "Interview with Mayor Michael Bloomberg," September 12, 2011.
* "Rebuilding Ground Zero," with guests Larry Silverstein, Chris Ward, David Childs, Daniel Libeskind, Paul Goldberger, Michael Arad, September 13, 2011.
* PBS, "Frontline: Sacred Ground," produced by Nick Rosen, directed by Kevin Sim, transcript of show aired September 4, 2004.
* PBS "Frontline: America Rebuilds: A Year at Ground Zero," transcript of show aired September 11, 2006.
* CBS News, "60 Minutes: What Ever Happened to Ground Zero?" written by 60 Minutes correspondent Scott Pelley, aired February 21, 2010.
* PBS, "Nova: Engineering Ground Zero," transcript of show aired September 7, 2011.
* Cornell University Regional Council, "Rebuilding the World Trade Center," panel discussion, New York City, July 18, 2011, DVD. A second panel discussion was held on March 8, 2012, DVD.
* Tanexis Productions, "16 Acres: Sacred Ground. Prime Real Estate. Battle Royale," transcript of the movie, September 10, 2012.
Accruals
As of August 2021, additional files, primarily of images and restricted files, are expected to be received in time from Sagalyn.
Manhattan (New York, N.Y.) -- History -- 21st century.; World Trade Center Site (New York, N.Y.); City planning -- New York (State) -- New York.; Economic assistance -- New York (State) -- New York.; Land use, urban -- New York (State) -- New York.; Public buildings -- New York (State) -- Design and construction.; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001.; Files (digital files); Financial documents.; Legal records.; Letters (correspondence); Minutes (administrative records); Proposals.; Reports.; Research notes.; Alliance for Downtown New York; Lower Manhattan Development Corporation; National September 11 Memorial & Museum (Organization); Port Authority of New York and New Jersey; Silverstein, Larry, 1931-
- Series I. Episodes (E) Files, 2000-2016; 2 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents
  "Episode," or E series files include newspaper articles (clippings, tear sheets, print-outs from newspaper websites or other on-line sources), miscellaneous primary and secondary materials (press releases, magazine articles), and some notes by Sagalyn related to various aspects of Ground Zero redevelopment.
  - EO. July leasehold sale to investor group, 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - E1. 9/11 Collapse, 2001-2002, 2014 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - E2. 9/11 Recovery Effort, 2001-2002, 2005 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - E3. 9/11 Corporate Reaction, 2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - E4. 9/11 Real Estate; E5. 9/11 Rebound (over time), 2001-2004, 2011 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - E6. Designs I; E7. Designs RFP II, 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - E8. Land Swap, 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - E9. New York Times Design Initiative, 2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - E10. Years Later (anniversaries, nostalgia). (3 folders), 2002-2014 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - E10-10. Tenth Anniversary (2 folders), 2005-2013 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - E11. Designs II, 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
    See also WTC Commercial Design Guidelines document in Series III, box 5, folder 3-4.
  - E11b. Semi-final Round, 2001-2003, 2011 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - E12. Libeskind Master Plan, including Implementation Struggles (slurry wall) (2 folders), 2003-2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - E13. Environmental Impact Study (EIS), 2003-2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - E15. Transit Building – Temporary PATH Station Rebuilding (Church Street), 2001-2003, 2008 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)
  - E17. Cultural Program ICI, 2003 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 20)
  - E19. Permanent Calatrava and PATH Station Design (2 folders), 2003-2015 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - E16. Expanding the Site (Deutsche Bank Building); E16b. 130 Liberty Deconstruction / Fire (2 folders), 2002-2008 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - E20. Freedom Tower Design (> Dec 16, 2003) / E24 Freedom Tower Redesign, Architects Battle (2003), 2003-2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - E21. Stalled/Delays, 2004-2013 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - E25. Cultural Buildings and Dissembling Events, 2004-2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - E25. Cultural Buildings and Dissembling Events / RB6. Rebuilding: Cultural, 2004-2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - E26. Construction Starts / Progress Steps, 2005-2013 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  - E27. Goldman Sachs Deal and Building; E28. Cortland & Dey Streets Debate, 2004-2008 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    See also Series V. Rebuilding Files for the related 2005 Goldman Sachs lease document.
  - E30. Power struggle: Bloomberg's calls and criticism of Silverstein, 2005-2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - E31. Pataki Deadline / Lease Renegotiations / Conflict leading to Episode E34, 2006 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - E32. PA takeover of project's construction management / PA problems with delivery of sites; E35. Paterson Timetable / News of Ward Reports, 2005-2009 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - E37. St. Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church resolution / deal collapse, 2001-2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - E40. Port Authority / Silverstein Financing Conflict, 2008-2010 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - E41. The "stumps" – podium; E 44. Third Amended to the Port Authority-Silverstein deal, 2010-2012 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - E45. Park51 Mosque Conflict, 2010-2011, 2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  - E46. 10th Anniversary / Memorial Plaza opening, 2010-2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    See also E10-10.
  - E47. Port Authority audit 2010, 2011-2012 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  - E50. Merrill Lynch/JP Morgan potential tenancy, 2007-2011 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - E51. Superstorm Sandy, 2012-2013 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
  - E53. Achievements / Openings, 2007-2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
  - E55. Openings of Rebuilt Facilities, 2011-2015 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
    Includes Greenwich Street/Courtlandt Way, PATH Terminal, Tower 4, Memorial Museum (see also E55.5 in Series VI), Liberty Park, and Miscellany.
  - E56. 3WTC Proposed Recast Deal, 2014-2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18)
  - Transit Hall articles and critique materials used for epilogue, 2003, 2014-2016 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 19)
- Series II. Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ), 1976-2015; 1.5 Linear feet
  The series includes primary documents related to the Port Authority, including Board resolutions, committee minutes, legal opinions, memorandums, reports created by the Port Authority and others, arbitration decisions, press releases, etc. While some material relates to the Port Authority generally, much if not most of this relates specifically to the rebuilding of the World Trade Center transportation hub and to chapter 15 (Transportation Phoenix) in Lynne Sagalyn's book. Primary documents also include summaries of interviews conducted by Sagalyn. The series also includes Sagalyn's chronologies, notes, article logs, and other work product based on these documents.
  Arrangement
  tbd
  - Two States in the Board Room, 1979-2000, 2013 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
    Documents underlying part of Chapter 4. Includes articles, etc. dated 1979-2000, with Sagalyn's 2013 chronology and log of WTC sale/privatization articles.
  - Privatization reports (2 folders), 1984-1995 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2-3)
    Includes reports from Bear Stearns, Chemical Securities, legal analyses, and others.
  - Port Authority document binder content (3 folders), 1993-2015. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4-6)
    Includes Board resolutions, agreements, memorandums of understanding (MOU), and other materials from 1993-2015. Also, includes Sagalyn's summary of actions at PANYNJ board meetings of October 2006-April 2009.